你准备好迎接另一个顶级行为了吗
are you ready for another top behavior
带上主管
bring on the supervisors
这一点
at this point
我们有kickstarter流程
we have the kickstarter process
链接到 Web 服务器进程
link to the web server process
所以如果网络服务器进程崩溃
so if the web server process crashes
现在启动了一个新的 Web 服务器进程
a new web server process is kick started now
不像http服务器
unlike http server
质押服务器和传感器服务器
the pledge server and sensor server
是顶级服务器进程
are top gen server processes
因此我们可以使用另一个
we can therefore use another
顶级行为调用主管开始
top behavior called supervisor to start
如果它们崩溃，监视并重新启动这些进程
monitor and restart these processes if they crash
将任命我们的服务主管
will name ours services supervisor
主管就像妈妈的手
a supervisor is like a mother hand
谁监视其他进程
who watches over other processes
通常被称为她的孩子
commonly refer to as her children
是的，一个高级主管可以监督一个
that's right an top supervisor can supervise one
或更多的性别过程
or more gender processes
我们稍后会看到可以监督
and as we'll see a bit later can supervise
其他主管进程
other supervisor processes
高层主管可以支持多种策略
top supervisors can support a variety of strategies
必要时重启子进程
for restarting the child processes if necessary
一种共同的策略是一种适用于所有人的策略
one common strategy is one for all
这意味着如果一个进程终止
which means if one process terminates
主管将终止所有
the supervisor will terminate all
其他孩子
the other children
并在他们的位置开始新的流程
and start new processes in their place
在我们的例子中
in our case
因为子进程不依赖于
since the child processes aren't dependent on
彼此我们将使用一对一的重启策略
each other we'll use the one for one restart strategy
这意味着如果子进程终止
which means if a child process terminates
仅重新启动该过程
only that process is restarted
毕竟
after all
我们不需要重新启动这两个进程
there's no need for us to restart both processes
让我们开始吧
so let's get started
让我们创建模块
let's create the module
文件名是服务主管
name of the file is services supervisor
这个名字没有魔法
and there's no magic to this name
这里服务主管
here services supervisor
当你真正使用魔法时
the magic comes when you actually use
主管行为
the supervisor behavior
现在，主管是其过程中的一个过程
now a supervisor is a process in its
像任何其他过程一样拥有权利
own right just like any other process
所以开始
so to start
主管进程将编写一个 rapper 函数
the supervisor process will write a rapper function
这次称为启动链接，您会明白为什么
this time called start link and you'll see why
一分钟后，我们将开始打印
in a minute and then we'll just start by printing out
启动服务主管
starting the services supervisor
启动主管进程
to start the supervisor process
你可能认为我们可以打电话给主管
you might think we could call supervisor
开始，因为这就是我们为生成服务器所做的
start because that's what we did for a gen server
但是主管模块没有定义开始
but the supervisor module doesn't define a start
功能它只有一个启动链接功能
function it only has a start link function
调用 start 链接会产生一个主管进程
calling start link spawns a supervisor process
并将其链接到调用它的进程
and links it to the process that calls this
在此处启动链接功能
start link function here
最初我们将从 ix 进程调用 start link
initially we'll call start link from the ix process
但稍后我们会写一个顶层
but later on we'll write a top level
主管进程
supervisor process
然后链接到这个主管进程
that then is linked to this supervisor process
现在类似于绅士过度行为的工作方式
now similar to how the gents over behavior works
主管行为
the supervisor behavior
还需要一个回调模块
also needs a callback module
这是启动链接的第一个参数
and that's the first argument to start link
这将是这个模块
and it's going to be this module
我们的服务主管
our services supervisor
然后我们将使用 ok 作为参数
and then we'll use ok as the argument
我们还要注册这个过程
and we're also going to register this process
与模块同名
under the same name as the module
所以我们使用名称选项
so we use the name option
然后我们希望它成为这个模块
and then we want it to be this module
现在
now
主管行为需要回调模块
the supervisor behavior expects the callback module
在编织功能中实现
to implement in a knit function
所以这是我们的下一步
so that's our next step
我们将进行模式匹配
and we'll pattern match on ok
只是因为我们把它传入
just because we pass that in
类似于 knit 如何与 gen 服务器一起使用
similar to how a knit works with gen server
和针织是
and knit is
当我们启动主管时自动调用
automatically invoked when we start the supervisor
在这里，因为我们通过了 ok 是第二个参数
here and because we passed ok is the second argument
好吧，它会通过它
well it's going to pass that in
针织是第一个论点
to a knit is the first argument
所以我们只是模式匹配它
so we just pattern match it
现在
now
nit 回调是我们告诉主管哪个
the nit callback is where we tell the supervisor which
过程或
processes or
孩子们需要开始然后监督
children it needs to start and then supervise
在我们的例子中，它负责两个子进程
in our case it's responsible for two child processes
我们会把它们放在一个列表中
and we'll put those in a list
是的，我们将列表称为孩子
yeah we'll call the list children
它将成为质押服务器
and it's going to be the pledge server
也服务
and also serve
传感器服务器
sensor server
然后我们需要打电话给主管
then we need to call supervisor
尼特
nit
我们将子列表作为第一个参数传递
we pass at the list of children as the first argument
然后我们也给它重启策略
and then we also give it the restart strategy
正如我们之前所说，我们将使用
and as we said earlier we're going to use the one
对于一个策略并注意那是一个原子
for one strategy and notice that that's an atom
所以让我们继续
so let's go ahead and
启动主管，看看会发生什么
fire up the supervisor to see what happens
超过 ix
over an ix
启动我们将使用的主管
to start the supervisor we would use
服务主管
services supervisor
我们的包装函数的名称是 start link
the name of our wrapper function is start link
好的，这将返回一个 pid
alright and that's going to return a pid
这将被包裹在两个拉
which is going to be wrapped in a two pull
好的 pid 我将调用 sub pid
okay the pid I'm going to call sub pid
就这样
just like that
哦，我们得到了空气
uh oh we get an air
好吧，它正在尝试调用质押服务器
well it's trying to invoke the pledge server
启动链接并传递一个空列表作为参数
start link and pass an empty list as the argument
我们会在我们的代码中注意到
we'll notice in our code
我们没有告诉主管如何开始
we didn't tell the supervisor how to start
子进程
the child processes
所以主管假设我们的
so the supervisor assumes our
代码遵循一些约定
code follows some conventions
当一个子进程
when a child process
启动它需要链接到主管
starts it needs to be linked to the supervisor
所以主管可以检测到崩溃
so the supervisor can detect a crash
所以主管认为孩子
so the supervisor assumes that the child
过程定义了一个开始
process defines a start
链接功能
link function
启动过程
that starts the process
并将其链接到当前进程
and links it to the current process
在这种情况下，这将是主管
which will be the supervisor in this case
如果我们查看我们的质押服务器
and if we look over in our pledge server
好吧，它不遵循该约定
well it doesn't follow that convention
它定义了零能力的起始函数
it defines a start function of ability zero
它不需要任何论据，也不会
it doesn't take any arguments and it doesn't do
任何链接，这与我们的传感器服务器相同
any linking and this is the same for our sensor server
启动功能
start function
所以这就是为什么我们得到空气
so that's why we get the air
因为主管正在寻找一个
because the supervisor is looking for a
启动链接功能
start link function
所以让我们解决这个问题
so let's fix that
我们将从头开始重命名这个接口函数
we'll rename this interface function from start
开始链接
to start link
然后而不是打电话
then instead of calling
gen 服务器启动链接
gen server start link
这将产生 gen 服务器进程和
that's going to spawn the gen server process and
链接它
link it
到调用我们的启动链接函数的进程
to the process that calls our start link function
并且主管将通过这个开始
and the supervisor is going to pass this start
链接功能
link function
在争论中，我们并不真正关心它是什么
in argument we don't really care what it is
我们将使用下划线 arg
we're just going to use underscore arg
但我们在空中看到了消息
but we saw in the air message
它只是一个空列表
it's just going to be an empty list
然后我们会
and then we'll
还在此顶部添加打印输出
also add a print out here at the top of this
因为我们现在没有
because we don't have one right now
它只是想说
it's just going to say
启动传感器服务器
starting the sensor server
当我们在这里的时候
while we're here
让我们把刷新间隔调低
let's crank the refresh interval way down
使 d bug 输出
so that the d bug output
不会妨碍我们所看到的
doesn't get in the way of what we're seeing when
该过程开始
the process is start
所以让我们把它设置为60分钟的间隔好吧
so let's put it on an interval of 60min okay
好吧，我们最后有评论
well we've got that commented at the end
所以我们就把它从这里拿走
so we'll just take it out of here
我们将评论我们的 5 秒间隔
we'll comment our 5 seconds interval
然后我们就可以了
and then we'll have it be
60 分钟这样我们就不会看到太多的调试了
60min that way we won't see as much debug
让我们也以同样的方式修复我们的质押服务器
let's also fix our pledge server in the same way
我们希望我们的接口函数是启动链接
we want our interface function to be start link
gen 服务器启动链接
gen server start link
哦，它需要忽略的论点
oh and it takes arguments which will ignore
现在我们正在遵守约定
now that we're following the conventions
主管应该高兴
the supervisor should be happy
所以让我们在这里重新尝试一下
so let's try that out in a clean slate here
好吧，让我们启动我们的服务主管
all right let's start up our services supervisor
啊，看起来好多了
ah that's looking a lot better
是的，我们看到服务主管
yeah we see the services supervisor
启动然后自动启动两个
starts and then automatically starts the two
子进程
child processes
这是指出主管的好时机
this is a good time to point out that the supervisor
模块本身
module itself
有一些方便的功能值得您保留
has some handy functions worth keeping in your back
例如口袋
pocket for example
假设我们想看看哪个
let's say we want to see which
孩子们在监督
children it's supervising
好吧，我们可以使用这个主管模块
well we can use this supervisor module
这不是服务主管
this isn't services supervisor
这只是一个内置的主管模块
this is just a built in supervisor module
它有一个叫做女巫孩子的功能
it has a function called witch children
然后我们将主管的 pid 传递给它
and then we pass it the pid of a supervisor
好吧，这就是我们的 pid
well that's our sup of pid
我们看到它有两个孩子传感器服务器
and we see that it has two children the sensor server
这是那个孩子的pid
here's the pid of that child
它说工人
it says worker
当你看到工人
and when you see worker
它仅表示主管以外的任何流程
it just means any process other than a supervisor
然后我们就有了我们的质押服务器
and then we've got our pledge server it's
pid，它也是一个工人
pid and it's also a worker
如果你愿意，你也可以数孩子
if you wanted you can also count the children
只需更改哪些孩子来计算孩子
just change which children to count children
我们看到我们有两个工人
and we see that we have two workers
所以让我们的传感器服务器崩溃
so let's crash our sensor server
是的，首先我们需要找到它
yeah first we need to find it
所以我们将使用 where is function
so we'll use that where is function
然后我们注册了我们的传感器服务器
and then we have our sensor server registered
在传感器服务器下
under sensor server
这将返回一个 pid
that's going to return a pid
然后这次我将使用管道
and then this time I'm just going to use a pipe
我将把它导入进程出口
I'm going to pipe it into process exit
因为第一个参数是猪
because the first argument of that is a pig
第二个参数是我们要退出的原因
the second argument is the reason we want to exit
我们将再次使用kaboom
and we'll use kaboom again
完美只有子进程重新启动
perfect only that child process got restarted
因为我们使用的是一对一重启策略
because we're using the one for one restart strategy
并且为了很好的衡量
and for good measure
让我们继续让质押服务器崩溃
let's go ahead and crash the pledge server
是的，我们在质押服务器下注册了它
yeah we have it registered under pledge server
所以我们也会用它
so we'll kaboom it as well
我们看到它重新启动
and we see that it gets restarted
呜呼
woo hoo
现在假设
now suppose
我们需要配置传感器服务器
we needed to configure the sensor server
什么时候开始
when it's started
例如设置刷新间隔
for example to set the refresh interval
好吧，因为我们不再启动传感器服务器
well since we're not starting the sensor server anymore
现在是主管的工作
that's now the supervisor's job
这是开始链接参数派上用场的地方
this is where the start link argument comes in handy
是的，我们想在这里传递刷新间隔
yeah we want to pass the refresh interval in here
作为这个弧
as this arc
为此，我们回到服务主管
to do that we come back over to the services supervisor
你注意到这个孩子的名单
and you notice this list of children
我们只是使用模块名称
we're just using module names
但另一种方法是使用
but another way to do this is to use a
元组第一个
tuple the first
元组的元素是模块传感器服务器
element of the tuple is the module sensor server
然后第二个元素将是一个参数
and then the second element is going to be an argument
所以在我们的例子中
so in our case
如果我们希望它是 60 分钟的刷新间隔
if we wanted it to be 60min refresh interval
我们可以使用 60
we could use 60
但这可能是任何论点
but this could be any argument
你可以在这里使用一个列表
you could use a list here
或地图或任何你需要的东西
or a map or whatever you need
配置您的服务器进程
to configure your server process
所以现在 60 将会通过
so now 60 is going to get passed
到我们的传感器服务器作为这个参数
over to our sensor server as this argument
所以这将是间隔
so this is going to be interval
然后我们就打印出来
and then we'll just print out
启动传感器服务器
starting the sensor server
和
with
间隔，我会说男人刷新
interval and I'll say men refresh
现在我们将在这里得到一张白纸
now we'll get a clean slate over here
启动我们的服务主管
fire up our services supervisor
你会看到它说启动传感器服务器
and you see it says starting the sensor server with
60分钟刷新
60min refresh
现在让它真正起作用
now for this to actually work
你需要把刷新间隔
you would need to put the refresh interval
在状态中，而不仅仅是使用模块属性
in the state rather than just using a module attribute
这是一个常数
which is a constant
但我们会把它作为练习留给你
but we'll leave that as an exercise for you
关键是你可以安排事情
the point is you can arrange things
以便主管通过
so that the supervisor passes
需要什么论据
whatever arguments are needed
给它的孩子
to its children
所以遵循惯例给了我们一个快风
so following the conventions gave us a quick wind
但有时你想在线条之外着色
but sometimes you want to color outside the lines
不明白怎么做
don't understand how to do that
让我们再深入一点
let's dig a little deeper
回到我们为主管服务
back over in our service to supervisor
我们初始化主管
we initialize the supervisor
有这样的孩子名单
with a list of children like this
注意我们不必告诉它如何开始
notice we didn't have to tell it how to start
每个子进程
each child process
那它怎么知道
so how does it know
所以看看这个调查承诺服务器
so check this out survey pledge server
我们知道那是一个 gen 服务器
we know that that's a gen server
以及当一个进程使用 gen 服务器行为时
and when a process uses the gen server behavior
我们已经看到一些
we've seen that some
函数自动注入
functions are automatically injected
进入模块
into the module
那么其中之一
well one of those
我们还没有看过的函数被调用
functions that we haven't looked at yet is called
子规格
child spec
所以默认情况下
so by default
当我们给主管一个这样的子模块时
when we give the supervisor a child module like this
像质押服务器
like pledge server
好吧，它调用了子规范函数
well it calls the child spec function
像这样传入一个空列表
passing in an empty list just like this
并返回所谓的子规范
and that returns what's called a child specification
这是一张灵药图
which is an elixir map
描述主管应该如何开始
describing how the supervisor should start
并监督子进程
and supervise the child process
你看这里有一个 id
you see it has an id here
那只是设置为服务质押服务器
that's just set to serve pledge server
这只是主管内部使用的
and that's just used internally by the supervisor
识别这个孩子
to identify this child
它也有重启
it also has restart
这表明何时终止的子进程
which indicates when a terminated child process
应该重新启动
should be restarted
现在是永久的，这就是它现在设置的
now permanent which is what it's set to right now
默认情况下，子进程总是重新启动
by default means the child process is always restarted
另一种选择是暂时的
another option is temporary
这表明子进程不应该
which indicates the child process should never
重新启动它也已关闭
be restarted it also has shut down
这表明子进程应该如何
which indicates how a child process should be
终止这是一个超时值
terminated this is a timeout value
我们看到它有一个类型，那就是一个工人
we see it's got a type and that's a worker
因为这不是主管
because this isn't a supervisor
这是一个常规的性别化过程
it's a regular gendered process
然后这是它如何开始的关键
and then here's the key to how it gets started
我们看到开始键的值是一个元组
we see that the start key has a value that's a tuple
其中第一个元素是模块
where the first element is the module
第二个元素是功能
the second element is the function
跑步
to run
然后第三个元素是参数列表
and then the third element is a list of arguments
好吧，它会传递一个空列表
well it's going to pass an empty list
所以参数列表
so the list of arguments
默认情况下只是一个参数
is just one argument up by default
这是一个空列表本身
which is an empty list itself
所以这通常被称为 mmafa
so this is typically referred to as the mmafa
模块功能
module function
然后是论点
and then the argument
并鉴于该信息
and given that information
这个主管知道如何启动这个子进程
this supervisor knows how to start this child process
您可以将子规范视为
you can think of a child spec as a
主管用来生成其孩子的配方
recipe the supervisor uses to spawn its children
现在默认子规格工作
now the default child specs work
非常适合我们的应用程序
great for the purposes of our application
但我们会给你一些起点
but we'll give you some starting points
所以你知道如何根据需要进行定制
so you know how to customize if need be
例如，如果你想改变怎么办
for example what if you wanted to change
从永久重启到临时
restart from permanent to temporary
好吧，我就复制一下
well I'll just copy this out
我们会回来这里我们会去我们的承诺服务器
we'll come back over here we'll go to our pledge server
然后当我们使用
and then when we use
gen server 我们可以增加一些选项
gen server we can tack on some options
我们要说重启现在是暂时的
we're going to say restart is now temporary
通过这样做，我们将覆盖
and by doing this we're going to override
默认重启
the default restart
那在默认孩子的背上
that's in the default child's back
如果我们把它保存起来
if we save that away
回到这里，我们重新加载
come back over here and we reload
调查承诺服务器
survey pledge server
我们再次查看它的子规格
and we look at its child spec again
通过调用该子规范函数
by calling that child spec function
看看重启现在是暂时的
well look at that restart is now temporary
现在更进一步
now taking it a step further
如果你想改变一堆这些默认值
if you wanted to change a bunch of these defaults
您可以覆盖默认的子规范功能
you can override the default child spec function
所以你可以拿这张地图我就
so you can just take this map I'll just
把这整件事复制到这里
copy this whole thing here
我们将回到我们的质押服务器
we'll come back over to our pledge server
然后我要删除这个
and then I'm going to remove this
因为我不只是想覆盖它
because I don't just want to override that
我要定义我自己的子规范函数
and I'm going to define my own child spec function
这是儿童规格
it's child spec
它需要一个组织
it takes an org
然后你就像那样粘贴那个地图
and then you just paste that map in just like that
并更改您想要的任何这些值
and change any of these values you want
接着
and then
当主管调用子规范函数时
when the supervisor calls the child spec function
好吧，它会得到你所有的覆盖
well it'll get all your overrides
拥有这些知识
armed with this knowledge
你有很大的灵活性
you have a lot of flexibility when it comes to
覆盖自定义行为的默认值
overriding the defaults for custom behavior
现在我们不需要这种级别的定制
now we don't need this level of customization
所以我要在继续之前删除它
so I'm just going to remove this before moving on